“Loving the Silent Tears”
was a phenomenal show…
If ever the notion of world peace were
to ever find its way to the stage,
it would be in the form
of “Loving the Silent Tears.”
… “Loving the Silent Tears”
happening at the Shrine Auditorium.
The musical “Loving the Silent Tears”
is coming to Los Angeles.
Kay Tse,
the famous singer from Hong Kong,
has been invited
to join the musical in the USA.
…internationally known spiritual Master,
Master Ching Hai.
Supreme Master Ching Hai
is a world-renowned spiritual teacher…
… Master Ching Hai.
… it’s called “Loving the Silent Tears.”
Don’t miss the musical
“Loving the Silent Tears”…
Director Vincent Paterson…
… the 19th Anniversary
of Supreme Master Ching Hai Day.
“Loving the Silent Tears.”
This new musical has certainly
made its presence known in Los Angeles.
The Shrine Auditorium
in Los Angeles hosted…
… celebrating the work
of Supreme Master Ching Hai.
Honoring the benevolent work
of the world-renowned spiritual teacher.
We’re here live at the red carpet
of “Loving the Silent Tears.”
It’s a musical
that brings all the international superstars
to one place – and that’s here.
The Oscar-winning actor
from “West Side Story,”
George Chakiris!
Former Miss USA, Susie Castillo!
... “The Lost Boys,” Corey Feldman!
She’s a Tony winner
for Best Featured Actress in a Musical.
Debbie! Debbie! Over here!
Oh my God, you look so beautiful!
I’m so excited! I’m so excited.
It’s like, look at this!
Look what’s happening!
I’m so excited.
The carpet is so lively
and everyone’s ready to go.
It’s just a real celebration of world culture.
What’s amazing
when I was walking down the carpet,
there’s so many different cultures.
It’s great to be involved.
I just can’t believe
how big the production is.
Very excited,
there is so much spectacle and warmth.
It’s definitely unlike
any other red carpet I’ve been to.
How about you?
I’ve been in a couple of them.
The Oscars and the Grammys.
But this is different.
It’s very beautiful.
And you’ve been to
so many different red carpet events
here in Hollywood.
What do you think makes this one
stand out the most?
I mean, just,
let’s take a quick look around us.
Look at the outfits, for God’s sake.
Oh my God, it’s beautiful.
Have you ever seen anything like this?
THE RED CARPET
Pop icon Jon Secada!
Mr. Secada, straight over here!
And you’re a 2-time
Grammy Award winner?
Yes, yes, and I feel very excited
to be a part of this show.
Absolutely. And what made you decide
to get in as part of the project?
I think it’s the message itself.
Very happy that I wrote a song for it
along with the Supreme Master.
When I read the poem,
the message kind of spoke for itself:
love, forgiveness, understanding.
Those messages we need today
more than ever.
Absolutely.
And those messages are so universal.
We can relate to them
no matter what culture we’re from,
right?
No matter what.
I’m here at the renowned
Shrine Auditorium in Los Angeles.
It has held the Oscar
and Grammy Award ceremonies.
“Loving the Silent Tears” will soon
premiere at this auditorium.
We can say that the most professional,
most beloved, most successful people
in theatre and the musical world
are here today.
Grammy Award winners,
Tony Award winners,
directors and producers and composers
who have won awards
from all around the world,
pouring their hearts and souls
into one musical.
Emmy-winning Doug Katsaros!
Creative collaborations can be tough,
and this one was just magical.
It’s an astonishing group of people
that they have pulled together.
Emmy-winning choreographer
of “High School Musical,”
Bonnie Story!
… and Madonna’s world concert tours,
Vincent Paterson!
The execution from Vincent Paterson.
I mean, he worked
with Michael Jackson for 17 years,
c’mon!
You know, it’s amazing.
Bonnie Story’s choreography,
the arrangements from Doug Katsaros,
all the composers, Oscar, Emmy,
Tony winners, Grammy winners,
and little old me.
Yeah. It’s a thrill.
Two-time Oscar winning composer
Al Kasha!
Here, Mr. Kasha!
I created the show.
I wanted to think of a show
that would reach the whole world,
16 countries and 6 continents.
Dance styles are very different
in different countries.
How did you even start
putting together a choreography piece
for this?
Well, I did a lot of research.
A lot of research.
Jody Watley, Grammy-winning pop...
Jody!
Vincent Paterson as our director…
It’s a dream come true for me
to have met him now
and worked with him.
It’s been nothing but joyful
and full of love.
So, I hope that comes across
to the audience,
and I hope they feel the same way
that we do.
Look at this! Beautiful!
There is such beautiful energy here.
The atmosphere is bursting
in excitement
as thousands of theatregoers arrive,
including Hollywood celebrities.
This musical has assembled
many Broadway stars
and famous singers
from around the world.
Now, let’s see who will show up
on the red carpet.
It’s going to be a beautiful night, everyone.
This is all about peace, love, and goodwill.
So tonight I am an ambassador
for all three.
Before I was on “NCIS: Los Angeles,”
I was on Broadway,
so music and theatre and dance
is very a part of me.
Showed a lot of interest in this show,
heard a lot about it,
so I thought I’d come down
and enjoy the arts.
Star of “Leave It to Beaver,” Jerry Mathers!
This is going to be a very interesting event.
It’s so multicultural.
There are so many different things
that are going to be going on in this show,
so many very, very talented people,
that I can’t wait to see it.
I wouldn’t have given this a miss
for anything.
I’ve been looking forward to seeing this
ever since I heard about it.
Really great.
I’ve never been to anything
like this before.
I just came like three days ago from Paris.
Did you come particularly for this event or?
Definitely, I did. Just for this event.
I enjoyed your work on “Chuck”
for many years. You’re fantastic.
What made you want to be
a part of this event?
It was based on just a feeling that
I should be out here,
and hopefully I’ll learn something.
Siavash!
Persian pop superstar!
The energy is wonderful.
And bravo,
Supreme Master Ching Hai.
Such a beautiful poem.
This is a semi-historical situation
for this one piece.
We have representation of Iran,
of Lebanon, and Israel
for the first time on stage together.
Award-winning singer of peace,
Liel Kolet!
… Camellia Abou-Odah!
It’s time for people to embrace
the higher concept of peace.
This is a really powerful moment for me,
and just to be able to sing with them
on the same stage
is just a proof that
we can have peace in this world.
See, when politics puts walls between us,
I think it is a good time
to break the walls with music.
… “Baywatch,” Kelly Packard!
Do you follow the teachings
of Master Ching Hai?
Yes, I am a big fan.
And I think she’s so wonderful
and so eloquently spoken.
And this is going to be beautiful
to be able to take her words
and make them into a musical.
I got a copy
of the “Silent Tears,” the poems,
and I just was floored.
Her and her teachings,
it’s so beautiful.
Absolutely peace and love,
I mean, she just emulates that.
When you’re inspired by poetry
in the way that Al Kasha was,
tremendous things happen.
I am very honored to be a part
of this extraordinary event
and celebrating the 19th Anniversary
of [Supreme Master] Ching Hai Day.
Today’s event is a beautiful, spiritual,
uplifting, amazing…
It’s a true representation of world peace
and all beings being one.
All beings on this planet have the right
to live in peace and harmony together.
That’s right.
Dignified, prestigious event.
Supreme Master Ching Hai
is high on my list.
Anybody who services love, peace,
goodwill towards men, to fellow man,
is right up there in my book.
Supreme Master Ching Hai!
My name is Gina La Piana,
we are so pleased and honored
to be here to share your day with you.
Greetings, Supreme Master Ching Hai!
Supreme Master Ching Hai,
Happy Anniversary. Congratulations.
Congratulations
on your 19th Anniversary
for Supreme Master Ching Hai Day.
What a great job.
Happy that this wonderful day has
come to pass.
You are a beacon in the world today.
And I’m very proud
of what you’re doing for everybody.
… and tell her
I’m a big fan of her work.
Thank you for all you do
to bring compassion
to our wonderful world.
We think that you’re just wonderful.
Congratulations
on your 19th Anniversary.
I’m looking forward to 90.
Supreme Master Ching Hai Day,
this is a fabulous event
and we’re honored to be here.
I’m really here
to celebrate the 19th Anniversary
of the Supreme Master.
I think it’s great, a great salute.
And I think it’s a great salute
to the Supreme Master.
Golden Globe and Emmy winner
Brenda Vaccaro.
I’m looking to find my inner peace.
If we can’t find our inner peace
after all this…!
Tony-winning actor, dancer, and singer
from “Billy Elliot the Musical,”
Kiril Kulish!
I appreciate everything
Supreme Master has done and is doing.
It’s really, really inspiring
and a great message,
and I think
the whole world needs some of it.
She’s a Chinese platinum pop star
and a vegetarian.
Right here, Kay!
Right in front of you.
Could you turn this way?
You are a jewel of the Orient.
Wow, thank you!
This is the first time I've attended
a Hollywood red carpet.
I’m very excited.
People from all around the world
have come here to support us,
so I’m very happy.
No matter where you’re from,
no matter what language you speak,
everyone is looking for a path
to spiritual betterment.
And this musical has embodied
the search that all of us go on:
“What is the meaning of life?
What happens to me?
Why am I here?”
I hope that this is the start of a trend.
Aulacese [Vietnamese] pop star
Hồ Quỳnh Hương!
It’s a spiritual journey
from the lead characters.
All the different countries are there
to help them along their way.
Ms. Callaway, over here!
I’m very happy to be
representing the continent of Australia.
It’s going to be fantastic.
Fabiana!
I’m from Brazil,
representing my country of Brazil
with the samba.
Can you show us
some sample samba moves?
Sure!
Beautiful!
I’m up in the air
playing a harp and singing,
and I have my own troupe
of Irish dancers.
And really, it’s like being a queen.
We’re using our cultures
to really share it (the message)
with as many people as possible.
So I’m really, really honored.
Korean pop star Brian Joo!
Hi, Brian!
Oh my God, I want to tell you
I wanted to meet you so much tonight.
Oh really?
Yeah, because you started
the whole K-pop thing, man.
Look, you have so many fans
surrounding us right now.
This is mind-blowing right now,
I did not expect this at all.
Today, the musical
is about all these international countries
coming together for peace,
and we’re singing poems, the poetry
from Supreme Master Ching Hai.
We speak up
for all the Caribbean people
all over the world.
This event is really
a special event for us.
Unity and one love.
All respect due
to the Supreme Master Ching Hai.
I love her. I’ve never met her before,
but it would be a pleasure to meet her.
I’d like to really sit down
and just look at her.
In the fantasy of the story,
I play this French…
I look a little bit like Snow White,
I think, in my dress. I love the dress.
And the song is called
“Accept Me the Way I Am.”
We’re doing it part in French,
part in English
so that everyone
can understand the message.
A bit on the left, please, that’s it.
It’s not often
that musicals at that level
are conveying a message so powerful.
So I really am glad to be part of this.
Also, the proceeds will be contributed
to three different charity organizations
including our friends that need help,
the animal care organizations,
so I think it is a big event
that we should support today.
Of course, promoting veganism,
which the Supreme Master is
so wonderful about.
You said you are a vegetarian.
What made you want to
take that step?
Eight years ago, it was something
that I really wanted to try,
being the animal lover and activist
that I am. So I just did it.
And I was so amazed
at how much easier it was
than I thought it was going to be.
And I felt, spiritually,
I just felt so great.
And I think they’re changing my mind
to become a vegan actually.
That’s fantastic!
Because everybody is so happy
and healthy.
Ladies and gentlemen,
Patti Cohenour!
Mr. Luke Eberl! … Junior Case.
Oh, excited. Just a little nervous,
but it’s okay!
It’s going to be really fun.
It’s a musical extravaganza.
Oh, it’s an extravaganza.
So much to look at, so much to take in.
So I know everyone’s going to
have a wonderful time.
Viewers absolutely cannot wait
for “Loving the Silent Tears.”
What can they expect?
They can just expect
the most beautiful,
over-the-top dancing, singing.
It’s a very touching musical.
Maybe you may need one or two tissues.
It’s been one
of the most rewarding experiences
of my career,
and I’ve done a lot of great things.
Now, we’ve all seen shows like “Cats”
with singing and dancing,
and this show will have all of that.
But underneath it all,
there is a deeper layer,
a spiritual journey, a human journey
that will touch the hearts
of its audience.
The wonder, the magic –
that is everything
about “Loving the Silent Tears.”
It’s finally happening.
Ready to work my arms.
This is going to be a spectacular evening.
I think there’s going to be
some real fun surprises as well.
It’s going to be a really unique
and exciting show to watch.
It will be unforgettable.
I just can’t wait.
Ready to go!
Have fun!
Good evening, ladies and gentlemen,
and welcome
to “Loving the Silent Tears.”
Ladies and gentlemen,
please welcome
2-time Emmy Award-winning actor
and vegetarian Kristoff St. John,
and vegetarian actress
and television host Kelly Packard.
Good evening, beautiful audience tonight.
And these are gifts from Heaven, right?
They sure are.
“Silent Tears,” a poetry collection
by Supreme Master Ching Hai…
and the program book
for tonight’s show.
All right, Dream World Cirque,
ladies and gentlemen.
The aerialists were Jena Carpenter
and Kyle DesChamps!
Give it up for them!
I got to be honest with you,
I am so wishing that
I could fly like that, Kelly.
How many good deeds do you need to do
to become an angel, do you know?
I don’t know.
Because if it’s one or less, you know,
I’m totally in. Right?
You do good deeds all the time!
You’re a vegetarian.
Woa! And so are you!
All right.
Today, we are excited and we are honored
to see all of you here tonight,
including government officials,
media members,
and celebrities among us.
We also want to thank
all of the international fans and media
flying in for the fantastic show ahead.
Yes, and we’d like to give a big hallo
to the worldwide viewers
watching live right now.
Hallo!
It is, it’s certainly remarkable
in this day and age
with technology
making this truly a global event.
A global event, that’s right.
“Loving the Silent Tears,”
the new musical
that we’re all excited to see,
it’s a tribute
to a vegan spiritual teacher,
a humanitarian, a poet, and an artist,
whose work uplifts and inspires:
Supreme Master Ching Hai.
And the show commemorates
the 19th Anniversary
of The Supreme Master Ching Hai Day
to honor her humanitarian works
and advocacy of peace.
Yes, and for today’s…
Yes, again, yes.
For today’s celebration,
we are joined by an important guest
who would like to convey his appreciation
to the Supreme Master Ching Hai.
Please welcome California State Senator,
The Honorable Curren Price.
Hallo, it’s an honor to be with you.
I want to give you greetings
from the 26th Senate District
here in the State of California,
and as chair of the Joint Committee
on the Arts.
It really is a pleasure
to welcome you here
to this wonderful celebration,
as we celebrate the grand poetry
and the works
of Supreme Master Ching Hai.
I think it’s significant
that we are here in Los Angeles,
the multicultural, multiethnic capital
of the world,
and we know that
you will enjoy this program.
And it’s an apt
and a very important tribute
to a woman who has demonstrated
her commitment to humanity,
to the arts, and to our society.
So I hope you will enjoy the show.
Thank you.
And now, ladies and gentlemen,
please welcome vegan television host,
actress, and former Miss USA
Susie Castillo,
and vegetarian award-winning actor
Corey Feldman.
Well, hallo there!
How are you all doing?
All the way back there!
It’s great to be here today
with everyone –
and of course
with my beautiful co-host Susie.
Well, thank you very much,
Mr. Corey,
and I am excited to be here
on so many levels.
Not only am I a big fan of yours,
of course, growing up (Thank you.)
watching your films and everything,
but this musical is going to be
absolutely fantastic.
You bet it is. (Yes.)
I can’t wait!
“Loving the Silent Tears” is based
on the poem collection
titled “Silent Tears,” written
by Supreme Master Ching Hai
years ago in her 30s.
Yes, and 2-time Oscar-winning
composer Al Kasha,
who is here today in the audience…
Very talented man.
That’s right!
Al Kasha was actually inspired
by the idea
of turning her profound, heartfelt,
and humorous poems into a musical.
It’s really, really so special.
So now, everybody, get ready
for one incredible journey
around the world to 16 countries –
all on one stage.
Yes, and thank God
it’s a really big one.
Yes, thank God for that.
We’re going to fit them all on here.
Yes, we are.
Before we enjoy the musical,
we would like to introduce
our very, very special guest speaker.
That’s right. Generations know him
for his Oscar-winning role
as Bernardo in the musical film classic,
“West Side Story.”
A living legend.
Please welcome
the wonderful George Chakiris!
Thank you.
Hallo! Hi, everybody.
Hallo, everybody.
I’m happy to be here this evening.
I have had the privilege
of performing in the theatre
for many years.
“West Side Story” was
a life-changing experience for me.
I’ve loved acting, singing, and dancing
since I was a kid.
And I’m pleased today to tell you
about someone
who has a great appreciation for the arts.
She is herself
an accomplished poet and artist.
But she is known throughout the world
as a spiritual teacher and humanitarian.
I admire the noble values which
Supreme Master Ching Hai represents.
Today is the celebration
of the 19th Anniversary
of Supreme Master Ching Hai Day.
This day was proclaimed in 1993
by Honolulu Mayor Frank F. Fasi
who wished to honor her
for her philanthropic contributions.
All around the globe,
Supreme Master Ching Hai has helped
disaster victims, the homeless,
orphans, veterans,
and many, many others.
She also loves the arts
because it’s the arts
that bring us together.
We are all here tonight for the premiere
of “Loving the Silent Tears,”
an international musical.
And Supreme Master Ching Hai’s
message is that
all beings are the same,
human or animal,
and have the right
to live in peace and dignity
on this beautiful planet;
and that each person can
do his or her part
to save lives, better our planet,
and be heroes.
And my personal way to be a hero
and save these important,
incredible lives
is to be a vegetarian.
It is in this caring spirit that
this celebration
of the 19th Anniversary
of Supreme Master Ching Hai Day
takes place.
And I now invite you
to watch this video greeting
by the inspirational lady herself,
Supreme Master Ching Hai.
Thank you.
The Inspiration
A Message
from Supreme Master Ching Hai
Greetings and love!
My sincere thanks to all
who give your heart
to this music assembly.
Congratulations to you
and the audience
for this rare and joyful event.
It is good that we still can celebrate
in whichever way
to beautify life on Earth as given by God.
It is good that we still love,
still enjoy, still share our goodness
to all that coexist
in this world and the next.
It is good that
we still believe in everything
that is noble and positive,
and Heavenly power will
definitely prevail.
To all involved in this musical event,
blessed be your dedication
to make this world
a more enjoyable place,
cheering up the masses
and giving thanks
to Heaven and Earth in this way.
Though I possibly couldn’t watch the event,
and though I am not aware
of the content of this program
in advance,
I trust that it will be great,
and all who watch it
will enjoy hugely.
Sorry there is no high tech where I do
intensive meditation at present,
so this simple message will serve
to convey my gratitude to you all.
I wish you success, happiness.
And as a token of love,
I share with you good news.
Maybe just to help pacify
all worrying hearts,
all hearts that are concerned
about the survival and wellness
of all in this world.
And that good news is
our planet will still be blessed
to exist for 10,000 years more to come
and continue, depending
on our goodness in the future.
And for that praised be God.
Thanks to all co-inhabitants’
loving prayers and contributions
in different aspects.
As for my humble self,
my humble self also continues her best
to support our common united endeavor
to save this planet
for this generation and countless next.
Enjoy the show,
thank you all again!
May God bless the universe
and protect our world.
Love you!
Oh, Lord
it’s said that You are everywhere.
Why is it that in my house
You never set foot?
Oh, Lord the veil seems
forever hanging there,
In front of my eyes.
O Lord of the Blissful Worlds
Pray rend it aside!
So I may behold Your Face.
O Lord of the Blissful Worlds
It’s said that You are everywhere.
Why is it that in my house
You never set foot?
You pour light on the entire creation
But leave me alone in darkness!
My soul cries and cries
till it finally breaks.
You wouldn’t care.
Oh, Lord
It’s said that You are everywhere.
Why is it that in my house
You never set foot?
I know, I’m far from being worthy
But I can assure You, no one is!
So loving Lord, do not tarry,
Pray pull me out of the dark pit.
Let me live in Your Light.
Let me live in Your boundless Grace.
Oh, Lord
It’s said that You are everywhere.
Why is it that in my house
You never set foot?
Oh, Lord the veil seems
forever hanging there,
In front of my eyes.
In front of my eyes...
O Lord of the Blissful Worlds
Pray rend it aside!
So I may step into eternal Life.
Life.
Diary of Joy?
Anyone? Diary of Joy?
The inner Master:
Symbol of eternal Life!
(The inner Master.)
The most powerful and gracious
of all beings in the cosmos.
The inner Master.
(The inner Master.)
Some call the Master:
Lord, the Father, Mother,
the Godhead, the Origin of all things.
(The inner Master.)
Some call it the Way,
others romantically describe Her
as the beautiful Bride, the Beloved.
Some say it’s your Real Face
before yesterday,
the Great Wisdom,
the Perfect Path, Love.
Call Him, Her whatever name you like!
(The inner Master.)
Frankly, He wouldn’t mind the least.
But no matter what it is,
One cannot live without.
And the longing to see Her is
the most agony of all
Only those who tread the mystic Tao
Know the pain of it.
And once it is found,
One realizes that
one has never known anything
like this (The inner Master)
The Way to enlightenment is
through the Light and Sound
The Heaven is within --
here and now!
Here and now!
No, it’s not!
Yours?
Yes.
Identify it.
It’s mine.
“Diary of Joy”?
I’m Joy.
Right. Pure joy.
So, did you write that poem?
No. I copied it down years ago.
It was a foolish thing to do.
It doesn’t mean a thing to me.
Okay. Why are you traveling today?
Visiting family?
That’s none of your business.
Just passing time.
How can anyone tell
where they’re going here?
The train schedule’s unreadable.
It looks like there’s only one train!
And everyone has such unusual style.
So you don’t even know
where you’re going.
I was going to the train station.
Just not this one.
I’ve never seen this one before
in my life.
It certainly wasn’t the station
I wanted.
The cab driver must have been
completely incompetent.
Where is this train going?
Everywhere.
No, really.
Really, everywhere.
Bye, Dad!
Bye, Dad.
Exactly where is this train headed?
All aboard!
Oh! I want off. Now!
You were intending on traveling, right?
Find your seats!
Excuse me, ma’am.
Get your hands off my book!
I mean my bag. Bozo.
I’m sorry.
Everyone says I’m clumsy.
Everyone’s right.
Well, mostly it’s my dad.
He says that.
Grow up, Bozo, and don’t complain
about family to me.
And don’t be asking me for a ticket.
Dragged off to who knows where.
To magic! Wonder!
All sorts of discoveries!
Realizations that open the heart.
Tickets, please!
Wouldn’t You accept me the way I am?
Your hard tests are so difficult to pass!
You know well what it’s like
To live in this dark world
without Your guide
Wouldn’t You accept me the way I am?
Your hard tests are difficult to pass!
I value You alone and no one else!
This You must have known since long ago.
O Master of heaven and earth,
Lord of infinite Love,
High above all sorrows and pleasures
You own my very heart!
Wouldn’t You accept him the way he is?
Your hard tests are difficult to pass!
Wouldn’t You accept her the way she is?
If You’re not there to hold our hands
We’d fail immediately!
Wouldn’t You accept us the way we are?
Your hard tests are difficult to pass!
Accept me just the way…
Accept me just the way I am!
Nobody accepts me the way I am.
What just happened here?
(Nobody.)
Did anybody else see
what happened here?
We went through Paris!
I told you! Lots of things to see.
It was Paris! Paris, people!
Fabulous scenery!
But there’s more to experience!
Would you like a baguette?
A glass of “nectar”?
Huh?
Would you like some juice?
It’s happening again!
Are you hearing this?
Or is it just me?
Or maybe it’s something I had for breakfast.
While I am athirst in the desert of existence,
You’re drinking Nectar
somewhere in the heavenly abode!
If only I knew the road,
I’d go up there and snatch it immediately.
O Master,
Gloriest of all Glory!
Wouldn’t You consider it fair
To spill down just a few drops
Just a few drops
For me?
If only I know where You hide
I’d come running to seek.
But alas! As I’m born blind
Couldn’t climb the highest peak.
Even worse, being deaf and dumb
I can never call, nor hear Your voice.
O Jah (Lord),
You’ve created this poor soul
Everyone would tell me this.
So please take care of it.
Or it’ll die alone miserably.
You know it
Too well!
You have eyes
Come to fetch me.
You have a mouth
Please give me a call.
You have ears
Why not hear my plea?
You have eyes
Come to fetch me.
You have a mouth
Please give me a call.
You have ears
Why not hear my plea?
Master,
I’d like to make a deal with You:
We exchange roles for a few minutes.
Then You may discover a deep secret –
Or may just remember:
How painful to be separated
From Your very Self!
You have eyes
Come to fetch me.
You have a mouth
Please give me a call.
You have ears
Why not hear my plea?
You have eyes
Come to fetch me.
You have a mouth
Please give me a call.
You have ears
Why not hear my plea?
You have eyes
Come to fetch me.
(O Jah [God]! What are You doing)
You have a mouth
Please give me a call.
(alone in that great Heaven?)
You have ears
Why not hear my plea?
(Wouldn’t it be too lonely?!)
O Jah [God]!
Why not hear my plea?
You have ears
Well. Alone at last.
And with my sanity intact.
You got eyes, come and fetch me.
Or not quite.
You got a mouth, please give me a call.
A pair of drumsticks.
An old sweater.
A Diary of Joy.
Are you trying to get rid of this?
That bozo probably tried to steal it again.
Everything gets taken away from me.
Baggage only slows you down.
The best travelers travel light.
Of course, you could always get insurance.
Property insurance!
That’s a good idea.
No, no, no.
Spiritual insurance.
For your soul.
My soul needs insuring?
Somebody’s stealing my soul?
We all misplace things along the way.
Is it getting chilly in here?
Suddenly, yes.
Mercy, mercy.
Better luck in the next life.
The Master is more than just Kind.
O friends, I could never have enough time
To tell you of His boundless Grace.
Only in the remote corner of my heart
I humbly shed tears!
When Thou appearest,
The sun seems to fade!
Thy being
Shining as thousands of stars
and countless jewels,
Thy holy and youthful glow
Brighten the darkest corner of my soul.
O my longing heart,
Overfilled with joy!
And divine gladness.
While bathing in Thy infinite Splendor.
All worldly burdens
and sorrows,
depart!
While bathing in Thy infinite Splendor.
All worldly burdens and sorrows,
depart!
There is none in this world
Who’s so full of Love and Mercy.
It would be my great honour
To be just a swallow,
Standing on one leg,
Life after life
Singing Her praise!
Who is there to praise?
Who? What? Nothing!
Money!
My father always said
praise money! And I do.
Where have you been?
Growing up.
The next car over.
It’s the world of wealth!
I learned all about big-time investing.
Do you need some financial advice?
Or a tax shelter?
You got to protect yourself for the future!
Invest right.
Learn to handle money.
Bozo, you keep your hands off my money.
Pete.
What?
The name’s Pete, lady.
Whatever. I don’t have time
for boys your age.
All right. Well,
I am making my father proud.
And nothing is going to get me off track.
Oh, wow.
O Lord,
You have numerous disciples.
I have only You!
Who is the most faithful of us two?
I pity myself openly!
I complain openly!
Does anyone hear me? (I do!)
My Master wouldn’t care the least
Master
Master, You must have forgotten to
use Your human eyes
Now that the heavenly one is
no longer shut.
That’s why You do not see me
in my lonely corner
Longing to see You.
(I’m longing to see you, too.)
You embrace the glory of the higher worlds,
It wouldn’t matter
If I am groveling alone in this dark domain!
O Ye the “perfect” Saint,
Why are Your eyes lost?
Master! Do You have ears at all?
You must!
In order to hear my desperate call.
I think...
I’ll buy a pair of human ears for You
Tomorrow.
I suspect that
You’ve lost Your heart somewhere
While ascending the heavenly abodes!
Or else You’d recognize my feeling
As my heart is forever hanging
On my sleeves,
Dying to make itself an offering
To You!
Dearest Master,
Please sympathize with
All my fellow beings
who are on the same boat,
Who long for Nirvana,
But all they know is samsara.
Dearest Master,
In the case that
You’ve lost the human heart,
Please take mine.
Hey, lady, look what I landed!
Oh, Papa will be so proud.
Floozies, what next?
He’ll figure out how to juggle life.
I know already.
Oh, hey, watch this, baby!
Yes! Juggle knives!
Boys your age,
you think you’re immortal.
Men my age.
Start with oranges.
I could have done it.
Sure you could.
And what do you know about me?
I had a son.
You kids think you can do anything!
I can!
You take stupid risks!
And your family is left praying for you.
I’m going to be rich and famous!
And prayers go unanswered.
And the whole world will know my name!
And there is no God.
Or none worth forgiving.
And who needs God
when you have money?
And you end up alone
on a crowded street
looking for the face you won’t find.
The World is full of troubles
Only I’m so full of You!
If You were placed within the world
All the troubles would be removed.
But as the world is full of troubles,
I find no place for You!
No, Lord, I find no place for You.
The World is full of troubles
Only I’m so full of You!
If You were placed within the world
All the troubles would be removed.
But as the world is full of troubles,
I find no place for You!
No, Lord, I find no place for You.
If the worldly people know how to love You,
Their pains and sorrows would cease.
But I have discovered, dearest Master:
They’d rather love their pains and sorrows!
Oh, they’d rather love their pains
and sorrows!
The World is full of troubles
I find no place for You!
No, Lord, I find no place for You
The World is full of troubles
Only I’m so full of You!
If You were placed within the world
All the troubles would be removed.
But as the world is full of troubles,
I find no place for You!
I find no place for You.
Okay. Two cards.
Two cards or three?
Three cards for my friend
with the fat cigars.
Get lung cancer. See what I care.
Ignore that voice from the darkness.
We don’t know her.
Don’t want to know her.
Hey – the pot’s light.
Who didn’t ante up?
So, yeah, my dad taught me poker.
He’s a great poker player.
The greatest dad a guy could have.
Taught me how to toss back
five shots of vodka in a row.
And now we’re killing the liver.
Here, beautiful,
take this and go buy yourself
something pretty.
Hey! Keep your eyes on your cards.
She’s my personal property.
All right, who’s feeling rich?
Who thinks I’m not holding four aces?
All right. All right, I’ll see your bet
and I’ll raise you right through the roof,
and by the end of the night,
I’ll have enough money
to buy me ten more girls.
Hey! It’s my one and only!
I bet she empties your pockets.
Hey lady! What’s your problem?
Empty pockets!
Empty heart!
Empty mind.
I found my refuge in You.
And You have promised
everlasting happiness.
This I believe. Indeed I do!
Oh Master, hasten make it true.
For I’m dying in this prison
of the Prince of darkness.
Beloved Master,
You mean more than God to me!
You can move heaven and earth.
You can change demons
into Angels of Love.
Magician of the greatest worth
Why didn’t You change
this restless monkey mind of mine?!
Beloved Master,
You mean more than God to me!
Thy touch turns stone into gold,
And turns all demons into loving angels.
Pray mighty Master!
Touch my soul,
And turn it into Thine own.
If You don’t love me
I can love no one.
I know! I know it!
You long have told me:
“All beings are God’s creatures.”
Beloved Master,
You mean more than God to me!
And thank you so much, gentlemen,
it has been a blast!
Come on back,
you know where to find me!
We got to do this again.
You never know,
you can turn it all around.
Beginner’s luck, what can I say?
All right, all right, all right.
Okay. Fifty-seven hundred,
fifty-eight hundred,
fifty-nine hundred, six thousand…
No, I had a lot more than this.
Do you see any?
Did you see any fall on the floor?
Did it fall in her fist?
Enough!
Why are you always on me?!
I can’t decide if you’re a smart idiot
or a stupid genius.
Go pick on your own kid.
What’s his name?
Mama’s Little Boy?
Do you tuck him in at night?
Does he buy you flowers
on Mother’s Day?
Mr. Boy Scout who doesn’t drink.
And never gambles.
Yeah.
I bet he obeys your every command.
Oh, you have it all so good.
Yeah, I do have it good!
All you’ve got is a dusty old book
and some goody-two-shoes son.
And you’re alive and well
and living on this planet.
At last! Proof there is no God!
Eye masks, earplugs!
Who wants to take a nap?
In silence. Deep meditative silence.
Eye mask!
Earplugs! I’ve heard enough.
No charge.
They’re as hard as rocks.
They’ll soften up.
Sweet dreams. Say your prayers...
Wait for answers.
I thought we covered that!
There is no God,
or none worth waiting for.
Prayers? What a joke.
You want to see miracles happen?
Keep your eyes right here!
I’m the answer to everybody’s prayers.
Sleep tight.
Hallo Buddha, why do you cry?
In your stone heart how much desire?
Why do your tears stream down the sea?
Why give your love to the pebble?
Hallo Buddha, why do you cry?
In your stone heart how much desire?
Why do your tears stream down the sea?
Why give your love to the pebble?
Oh Buddha, oh Buddha,
Why did you leave Nirvana?
What is here to search for?
Endless pain or sorrow?
Oh Buddha, oh Buddha,
Hurry now, leave Samsara!
Back to where no sorrow
Only joy eternal
Only love, no border.
Oh Buddha, oh Buddha,
Hurry now, leave Samsara!
Back to where no sorrow
Only joy eternal
Only love, no border.
Hallo Buddha,
Why do you smile?
And your stone heart is full of light!
Why do your arms embrace the world?
Why does your love shine forever?
Oh Buddha, oh Buddha
Hey baby!
Where’s my lucky girl?
Could have used you out here!
I might need to get some of that cash back.
I’ll show you who’s a dimwit gambler.
You thought this was my life savings?
I got more.
Not a lot more...
anyway, I’ll win it all back tomorrow.
The book!
“Friday: He looks so handsome
in his sleep.”
“He looks so handsome in his sleep!”
You wrote a book about me!
Hey, lady!
Quit that! What are you doing?
You wrote a book about me!
I can’t hear you!
You wish.
In here!
Where here?
“Saturday: He turns twenty today.
I pray that angels visit his dreams.”
Give it!
Ohh. No, this is
about the mysterious son!
The famous Mister Perfect!
Give it here!
Why? What’s so secret?
Oh, stories from your dark past?
Lovers of the present!
A black eye in your future.
That’s pretty bold for an old lady.
Knock-knock!
Missed!
Safety is an illusion.
“Sunday – He still sleeps.
And my heart turns black.
Where are you, God?”
Oh, oh, oh – What’s this?
Oh, a poem!
“I am the mouthpiece
of the entire creation.”
I’m going to call the conductor.
Conductor!
He’s going to throw you off this train.
And with any luck, you’ll land in Siberia.
I am the mouthpiece
Of the entire creation.
Voicing openly
Their sorrows and pains
Of life after life
in the ever rolling wheel of death.
Pray, Compassionate Master
Hasten to put it to an end.
I am the mouthpiece
Of the entire creation.
Voicing openly
Their sorrows and pains
Of life after life
in the ever rolling wheel of death.
Pray, Compassionate Master
Hasten to put it to an end.
O Master of infinite Radiance!
Be gracious and shed a few beams
into my longing heart.
The world is a whirlpool,
Full of scorpions and snakes,
Which bite with lust, anger and hatred.
And people are drowning helplessly therein.
The world is a whirlpool,
Full of scorpions and snakes,
Which bite with lust, anger and hatred.
And people are drowning helplessly therein.
O Master, King of all the Kings,
Please take them back
to the mansion of Peace,
And restore to them the Eternal Spring.
When You cast Your lyrical glance
at somebody,
That person would believe
she is Your only beloved.
When You cast Your lyrical glance
at somebody,
That person would believe
she is Your only beloved.
O Loveliest of all the lovely!
Cast a hundred thousand glances on me.
I’d sell all the suns, the moons
and the stars in the universe,
Just to buy one of Your beautiful glances.
O Master of infinite Radiance!
Be gracious and shed a few beams
into my longing heart.
Hey, baby!
Wait. You’re mine!
Or – you’re with this loser?!
He has my book!
Hey, oh, that’s all my money!
I demand you get my diary!
No, that’s all I’ve got!
(Too bad.)
That’s all I’ve got!
Get my book!
Emergency stop. All stop!
Get your hands off my bag!
What are you…?! Oh!