International Gathering
with Supreme Master Ching Hai
Europe, Jul- Oct 2015
Share, share together.
So the more we use water, the more…
Inside. No problem, we have room.
And this is very light.
We’re like family here.
Yes, Master.
My secret.
Hmm, looks so nice.
It's like a dream, Master.
It's like a dream? (Yes.)
OK. Don’t wake up.
We have guests in the house,
so we cook for everybody.
Food’s ready. Yum, yum!
Delicious.
He ate already lunch and,
he ate his lunch already,
He just likes to feel the love.
OK, just a snack. All right?
Cheers! Cheers!
Cheers!
One, two, three.
What is that?
I cut it anyway.
I love you.
Love you. (See you, Master.)
BUDDHIST STORIES:
"GREAT-WEALTH
THE TREASURER'S SON"
OCTOBER 2, 2015
Hallo!
Are you guys all right there?
I see you very clearly. You see me?
Yes, very clearly.
Of course you can see me
without any help, any machine,
nothing.
OK, wonderful.
I can see you just like
right in front of me.
Wow! How come it's so clear here?
Why didn't you tell me earlier,
so we don't have to
struggle down there? (Yes.)
OK, then. You have enough room?
Yes? Everybody?
We’re good now.
OK. You can sit down.
Don't have to hide there.
Sit here or here.
You need to sit there
because there's no room, right?
Yes, we're good.
Oh, you're OK.
The guys you can handle, right?
You can sit on the window.
What did you eat today?
(Rice.)
We had a party,
a veg-party so many delicious foods…
(Oh?) fruits and…
Pie? What kind of pie?
What kind of pie?
We had a bread.
Bread? (Yes.)
Oh, I thought you said pie.
So bread, right?
Yes. We enjoyed the food very much.
OK, rice and vegetable
and protein and all that, right? (Yes.)
OK. Lucky people.
Thank you, Master.
Over here, what did you eat today?
(Noodles.)
Noodles fried or noodle soup?
(Fried.) Fried.
I wish I could eat both from here.
This food here,
and food there.
My God!
Is it raining a lot over there?
Oh, terrible here. Same, the whole day.
The whole day yesterday,
almost the whole day yesterday,
and now it's still raining.
Is it raining there also? (Yes.)
Wow! It's rainy
and very windy.
Even today I cannot let the big dog
go outside,
except when he has to go down
to do his business
and to eat something.
Otherwise he just stays indoors
because it's so terrible.
But that's just the beginning yet.
Beginning only, we will have
more trouble later, more rain.
So are you going tomorrow,
some of you? (Yes.)
How many go tomorrow?
(Three of us.)
Raise hands.
Oh, most of you go tomorrow.
All right.
Have a good trip.
You have a good trip.
Your holiday is very short this time.
I was thinking
it's the rain that makes the Internet
and the connection kaput.
Oh my God. Can you hear me at all?
I feel like it's choppy.
It's OK, Master.
OK. Because it's raining,
maybe that's why we couldn't
have a connection very well.
I had to go upstairs in this room.
It's good.
It's OK now, right?
Later we'll know.
I know.
We are upstairs here
and it's not equipped like downstairs.
So they are patching the ceiling
with something and this and that,
and the camera might fall off
and oh my God!
Or maybe the light will fall off.
It looks very professional
with all the tape.
You guys should use duct tape,
duct tape.
We have it here. (You have it?)
It's maybe…
Oh no, I'm not sure either.
It's falling, falling.
Wow, the Supreme Master's house,
very professional.
You saw it? You saw that?
Can they see it there? No,  they cannot.
Never mind.
They are trying to tape
the light reflector, two men.
Two men are busy with that.
I wish you could see it.
Very professional, what we have here.
Poor men. My God!
All right. If this thing falls off
I think we call it a day.
Or maybe you can just stay there
and hold it.
Take turns to hold it.
It keeps falling off again.
All right. Never mind.
So you meditate inside the house, right?
Inside the room is very comfortable,
right? (Yes.) Yes, OK.
It's good that
you are sent there
because over here it’s raining so much
you'd probably be wet all day.
You wouldn't have enough chance
to change your clothes.
And wherever you sat before
to meditate outside is all wet.
Even though we have tape
and we do everything possible
but it's still all wet.
So that's why I sent you on time.
Are you thanking me or not?
No, you're not. (Yes.)
You wish you were here, right?
It's a bit wet and the staircase
is slippery and all that.
It's not fun. It's not fun.
It's truly very rainy here,
all day long since yesterday, non-stop.
So it's good that you're there,
and warm and cozy.
And you have your bathroom
right inside your room. Convenient.
If you stay here,
it's impossible to take care of yourself.
Then we'd have to
buy everybody a raincoat,
and then we'd have to
buy everybody an umbrella.
And then, oh I don't know,
what else do we have to buy?
And boots! Rain boots.
Umbrella and rain coats and, oh man!
It's good that you are there.
If you have to leave tomorrow
or the next day,
have a good trip. (Yes.)
Everybody's there, right? (Yes.)
All the good, the bad
and the beautiful, are there.
My God! OK.
Now, I have this and we're perfect.
Now you can recognize your Master.
All right.
According to Buddhism
and the believers and the tradition,
when you read sutra and all that,
you have to put on incense, flowers,
and bow to the sutra first,
and thank all the Buddhas
and Bodhisattvas
in ten directions respectfully
before you read it.
And then you cover the sutra also
with (vegan) silk or beautiful cloth.
I just make it more popular,
more easy, simple.
I apologize to all the Buddhas.
I say,
"If I have done something wrong
according to the tradition,
my heart is full of respect.
It's just that I cannot always do that.
So please, all the sin,
whatever I have done wrong,
is all on me."
At least, other people,
when they hear the names of the Buddhas,
according to the sutra,
they will get benefit.
This story is called "Great-Wealth."
Great-Wealth is his name,
"The Treasurer's Son."
I hear this kind of noise, echo.
Do you hear very well there?
(Yes. Very well.)
Good, good. OK, then.
Having led neither the holy life
nor riches won while young.
This instruction was given
by the Buddha,
while he was in residence at Isipatana
with reference to Great-Wealth,
Mahadhana, the treasurer's son.
I don't know who the treasurer is.
Great-Wealth is a name,
Mahadhana, that's great wealth.
Great wealth in Sanskrit
I think means Mahadhana.
Great-Wealth, it appears,
was reborn at Benares
in a household worth 80 crores,
meaning probably millions,
millions of dollars.
Now his mother and father
thought to themselves.
It's choppy?
Can you hear me very well there?
(Yes.)
Not choppy, not disturbed?
Oh, one? Yes, no?
It's choppy sometimes
and we don't see you well.
OK. Then use
your wisdom eye to see me.
I see you very well.
It is because we don't have
good Internet here.
Over there, the Internet is better.
That's why before
I rented a room in a good hotel
so that we have like fast Internet,
non-interrupted.
We blame it on "collective karma."
OK. Now.
His mother and father,
I guess they were a rich family.
His mother and father
thought to themselves,
"We have a vast store of wealth
in our house
and there is no necessity that
our son should do anything else
than just enjoy himself
according to his own good pleasure."
Accordingly they had him
instructed in singing
and in the playing
of musical instruments.
You still can see me,
the whole body,
the whole face, right? (Yes.)
OK. Good.
And if you hear me choppy,
then please just don't care.
What else to do?
And later when you come home
this will be uploaded on the Internet
with everything for you.
I'm trying my best already,
but this is the world.
We don't always have everything
we want.
When I bought this house
I didn't think of the Internet or anything.
And even though we have the Internet
but it's not fast and not very good.
Normally I don't use it.
So accordingly, they had him instructed.
It means they let him learn singing
and in the playing of music.
And that was all the instruction
he received.
Likewise, in that same city,
in a household worth
80 crores of treasure,
also another rich family,
a daughter was born.
The same thought occurred to
her mother and her father also.
And they had her instructed
only in dancing and singing.
What a match!
When the two reached the proper age,
they were married with
the customary ceremonies.
In the course of time,
both their parents died
and then there were twice 80 crores
of treasures in the same house.
It was the custom
of the treasurer's son
to go thrice a day to wait upon the king.
One day a company of knaves who
lived in the city, thought to themselves,
"If this treasurer's son would
only get drunk,
it would be a fine thing for us.
Let us show him how to get drunk."
Oh, man.
Accordingly,
they procured strong drink,
put roast meat, salt and sugar
in the skirts of their clothing,
and taking roots and bulbs,
seated themselves
in a convenient place,
watching the path by which
the treasurer's son would
approach from the royal palace.
When they saw him approaching,
they began to drink strong drink,
placed particles of salt and sugar
in their mouths
and took the roots and bulbs
in their teeth and chewed them.
And they said,
"Live for a hundred years,
Master Treasurer's son."
They wished him a long life.
"With your help may we be enabled
to eat and drink to our hearts' content."
Hearing these words, the youth asked
the little page who followed him,
"What are these men drinking?"
"A certain drink, Master."
"Does it taste good?"
"Master, in this world of the living,
there is no kind of drink
to be had comparable to this,"
meaning it's a very good drink.
What about?
Must be, maybe alcohol and cocktail,
something like that.
They were trying, these people were bad.
They were trying to seduce him
into drinking strong liquor and all that,
like ruining him.
This is the problem, you see.
You see that?
Originally, this boy was a good boy.
He didn't even know what drink was.
And they just sat there,
right where he was passing by,
so that he'd be exposed
to this kind of bad drink,
bad kind of lifestyle.
It is a problem.
Same in our world nowadays.
Many bad things were introduced
to our young, innocent people
and that's how they fell into the trap
of bad life and then they cannot get out.
Or they get out with injury,
to their mental or emotional,
or physical life.
This is to be pitied.
So the parents must always take care,
must watch over their children well
and don't let them be prey
to this kind of company.
There was a sister
who used to cook Aulacese
(Vietnamese) food for me.
Every time she came,
she didn't want to go home.
And she had one, about 20 years old,
two sons,
and one 15 years old.
I kept telling her to go home
but she said, "No, no,"
and then she always
made an excuse to extend it.
So I’d have to scold her somehow,
otherwise she would never go.
These people, these sons are
still young,
they need somebody
to watch over them all the time
and check every day
if something happens.
Otherwise, at home they see
only one father or one mother.
And now they don't even have the father
because they've divorced,
so only the mother's there.
And if they don't see them,
don't see the mother even,
then they easily fall prey
to the bad society outside.
The thing is, at home is only one
person, the mother, to take care of them,
to tell them what's good from bad.
But outside are
big society, schools, many peers,
outside are many bars,
many restaurants,
they're all full of meat, and alcohol,
and drugs and things like that.
So even one against many already,
and her sons, only one,
only, so one or two against many.
That is very difficult already.
And if she keeps staying here
nearby me, which she likes,
of course I understand that.
Everybody likes to stay
and I don't blame her.
it's just that if we already have
made the bed, we lie on it.
We have children,
we have to take responsibility,
because their future is groomed
from childhood on already.
Wait until they fall into trouble,
then it's too late to correct.
And one trouble will lead
to another trouble
and we will not be able
to forgive ourselves.
If we didn't want any trouble
or didn't want a lot of work,
children are work, of course.
But nobody knows that
until they have them.
This is the problem.
Nobody tells them that
children are a problem.
Even if they told them,
when they're young, they're in love
and honeymoon, honeycake, whatever.
At that time, nobody can tell them what.
All these romantic visions about
having a handsome husband
and romantic couple
and have a couple of children
like everybody else,
and take the children to go to school
and then later they become somebody.
They don't know; they don't know.
And then the children grow up,
it's not the way they wanted.
They have their own personality.
And when they are young teenagers,
they just hate you for no reason.
And if you're not there,
they will listen to their buddies,
who sweet talk them into drinking
and drugging and smoking
and do all kinds of stupid things.
Or they go out
and have a big party, drinking
because they have reached 18.
They go out drinking
and then if one is drinking
the other dares them to take drugs
and then everything else
is born from there as well,
including unwedded children,
teenage mothers, etc., etc.,
or sometimes injuries,
wounding or death.
Because when they are drunk,
many things happen
beyond their control.
They are still at a tender age.
Even at 18 or 20, they're still tender
and really need somebody
always there for them.
You see, this poor treasurer's son,
normally he was a good boy.
He was married already
and he was happy
and he never did anything wrong.
And then they sat right
in the middle of the road somewhere
ambushing him with good drink
and good food,
and sweet talk, seducing him.
And then of course the boy
didn't know anything and asked,
"What is it? Is it good?"
and of course they said, "It's good."
Of course it might taste good,
but is it good for your body,
your mind, your spirit, or not,
that is another thing.
One time, there was
one follower of the Buddha,
the legend has it that one time
he took the Five Precepts,
like not harming others or killing others,
and not stealing, not telling lies,
not having illicit, I mean,
not improper sexual conduct,
and not drinking
and not taking intoxicants
like alcohol and drugs.
And then somebody,
I don't remember how it came to it
that he had to choose
to break one Precept.
So he thought, OK, he cannot kill,
he didn't want to kill.
He didn't want to have improper sex.
He didn't want to steal,
he didn't want to tell lies.
So he thought, OK, if he drinks alcohol,
then it's only harming himself.
He didn't even think it's harmful.
It looks good, drinking cool
and sitting and drinking
and then happy, happy, it looks like.
So he drank and then after that
he did, he broke all the Precepts.
Because alcohol somehow
brings the worst out of you.
Inside, all the bad qualities within you,
it makes them arise.
It will blind your reason,
numb your thinking
and then anything else you do
you don't even consider bad
or good, just anything.
That story was very bad,
but I don't want to really detail it here
because it's too bad.
All right, so this is the thing
about having company.
That's why we say,
"Show me your friends,
show me whom you are with,
then I know all about you."
It's like that.
So friends, we have to
choose very wisely.
It's just children sometimes,
they don't know who is good,
who is bad.
Even we adults, sometimes we are
also fooled by appearance,
and we don't know who is a bad friend,
who is a good friend,
and who is really, really good for us,
who is really bad for us.
Or who has ulterior motive
being our friend,
to want to be our friend,
things like that; it’s very difficult.
So many rich people or famous people,
they have tons of followers,
sweet talker and friends,
so-called friends, and all that.
And then you see that
quite a few of them
fall into a very detrimental lifestyle,
drugs, alcohol and abusive substances
and all that.
And some of them even end up
losing their life.
Quite famous, beautiful people,
young, wonderful people.
Many, you know that.
You read it in the newspaper, on TV.
This is a pity.
This is the thing about drugs,
alcohol, and that.
People always argue and say,
"Oh, we just take a little alcohol,
it doesn't matter.
We stay at home; we don't go out
and make any trouble."
But it starts always little.
It starts there
and if you can stop, then it's OK.
But you cannot.
Slowly and then because of drinking,
you attract the similar kind
of friends or buddies
and then it gets worse, gets worse.
And that's why people,
when they want to stop drinking,
they stop seeing these friends also.
Otherwise they cannot stop.
Or the smoking people,
when they want to stop smoking,
they stop, they try to avoid
the smoking group of people.
Otherwise they fall back again.
I saw some young people,
when I sometimes go out
in the restaurant and all that.
And then sometimes they told me things,
like the waiter, waitress,
they told me, they told me just talking,
and then I found out that so young,
only 18, already drinking a lot of…
because they told me how good is it,
this and that drink. And I said,
"Oh my God, you're so young!
Why are you drinking?"
He said, "Oh, because I like it."
I said, "But it's no good for you,
you know that."
He said, "Yes, but I'm still young,
I can still recover.
So it's better I drink now
than I drink when I am older."
I said, "But when you're older
you cannot stop anymore
because you're used to it.
Now you already like it.
Imagine if you keep drinking
like this until you're old.
Then how will you
be able to stop then?"
But they just reason with me, saying,
"Oh no, no problem. I can stop anytime."
I doubt it very much.
Smoking together and drinking…
smoke and drink together.
Imagine that.
But of course they don't listen to me.
But I still did say it,
every time I saw it I said it,
and sometimes it worked.
There was one… I went to eat
sometimes a vegan pizza.
I went to that shop sometimes
and because I gave good tips
they liked me,
so they trusted me
and all that, very good.
And then one of the waiters,
he worked in another restaurant,
but he had his girlfriend
in my restaurant.
His girlfriend liked me very much
because I was very polite to them
and I gave good tip,
and so she introduced me.
That day he was not working,
but he went to her restaurant,
and was drinking something
and smoking, waiting for her.
So she, because she liked me,
so she said,
"That's my boyfriend there."
And then I looked at him,
he was smoking
and drinking some alcohol.
So I said, "Hey, handsome!
What are you doing?
You like smoking, drinking?"
He said, "Yes."
I said, "Well, but you're
too handsome to do this."
And he said, "I know."
Because I called him handsome,
so he liked it.
And very sweet,
like a sister talks, or like a girly talk.
And he liked it.
They like me to call him handsome.
I said, "Oh you're too handsome
to do this.
This smoking, drinking
will make you wrinkle quickly
and then diminish your intelligence.
And then what will you do
with the girlfriend?
You'd better stay strong,
healthy, for your girlfriend.
And maybe you marry her
and then you have children
and then look at all the money
you spend on alcohol and drink.
You work so hard.
I know you're a hard-working person,
right?"
He said, "Yes, yes, yes,
I work hard for the future."
I said, "Yes, then you should save hard
for the future, because now you can.
What if you… tomorrow
you cannot work anymore, then how…
what happens to your girlfriend
or your wife or your future generation,
your future children and all that?"
And he said, "I know, I know,
but I, I got used to it."
I said, "Yes, I know that,
but it's just a habit.
If you stop, maybe you
acquire another habit. You could try."
Two weeks later I came back,
he said he stopped already
two weeks now. (Wow!)
And also another taxi driver
and another, another.
I cannot change
the whole world but wherever I go…
And then another two months later
I came back,
he was still was not smoking. (Wow!)
Yes, and also that taxi driver,
also, because I scolded him.
I give him very good tip,
so he also knows I'm a good person.
Then, because one time
he brought his son…
I told this story already, I think. (Yes.)
Then we don't bore you again.
And after many months I came back
the year after, he was clean of smoking.
But it was too late for his son,
his son was still smoking.
Because his son said
his friends are all smoking,
if he stops now it looks weird.
This is the problem,
with children,
teenager, they're proud
to be like everybody else.
"Are you chicken or what?"
And if you stop smoking
they will exclude you from their club,
whatever club that can be.
And then you're not cool anymore.
For being cool,
they're killing themselves.
This is terrible, terrible.
But nowadays
because of the smoking law,
somehow the children
know that it's bad now.
Look at that, the government steps in
and then it becomes like legal
not to smoke.
And then so they
can have good excuse.
Somehow the number of younger smokers
is reduced and drinkers also reduced.
Some pubs close.
Some pubs close, no one drinks a lot,
especially younger people.
I'm glad, of course we cannot
change the whole world overnight,
but it's some sign of change.
Whatever I can do,
anywhere I go privately,
I'm happy that it has
some effect on their people.
I scolded him, I said,
"Look at you, you smoke
and then that's why
your son learns after you.
You should be a better example.
You know how smoke
causes your cancer
and makes you die early
or makes you unable to work.
And your son, look he's only 15
and you already give him
cigarettes like that,
you smoke together
like buddy-buddy.
And then suppose you have cancer
or something next year,
who is going to take care of your son?
You're divorced,
he doesn't have a mother,
he relies on you and you make
a very bad example as a father.
I'm sorry if you're angry with me.
I have to tell you that
because I'm worried about your son."
And he stopped smoking
ever since then.
And I said, "How about your son?"
He said, "Sorry, he's still smoking
because it's not cool to stop in school."
"But at least," I said,
"at least you stopped
and maybe he'll follow."
So I bought him a Jesus cross,
silver, with a chain to hang on the neck.
I said, "This is to remind you,"
just to reward him,
I said, "This is to congratulate you."
One year later I met him on the street.
"Congratulate you
and then to remind you
not to fall back on smoking again.
Every time you want to smoke,
you touch the cross
and you pray to Jesus.
That's much better for you."
And then he liked that, and then,
I think he's still not smoking.
If one year, more than one year
he stopped smoking
then I am sure he'll be able to continue.
I say, "You have to be healthy
and strong for your son.
He's very young;
he has no mother now and only you.
And if you don't work,
what's going to happen to him?”
So he stopped.
Well, never mind.
And now we go back to India
with the Buddha. (Yes.)
I don't know how many more
I've said about smoking.
Everywhere I go, if I see that,
I tell them right away.
It's strange like that;
they're not angry with me even.
I thought I risk,
because strangers
sometimes I see in the restaurant,
I don't even know them,
they just sit next to my table.
I have actually no right
to tell them what to do.
I thought they're going to be angry,
but they all feel very apologetic.
They say, "Yes I know, I know, I've tried."
I say, "Try again, try again."
I talk sweetly. I don't say,
"Hey, no good, no good, no good."
Only that taxi driver,
because he was driving me
from my house to the city.
And then while we're passing
the path, mountain roads,
that his son was cutting grass
from my house,
he took the cigarette
and gave it to his son.
That's why I saw it, I said,
"This is…" I was really angry.
I was really angry.
Until then I didn't know that
he encouraged his son to smoke.
He passed by
and gave him one cigarette,
meanwhile we're waiting
for him to come back.
That's why I was angry,
so I really gave him… I gave it to him.
But the rest, because I don't know them,
I'm very sweet.
I say, "Oh, you've such a beautiful
and lovely skin. Why do you smoke?
You're going to destroy it.
Do you know how much the people pay
to have their skin beautiful?
You have such a beautiful,
beautiful face and pure skin.
I wish I had it.
And now you're smoking,
and soon, in several years
your skin will be very, very bad."
And that like motivates people,
something like that.
I don't always scold them
when smoking, no, no, of course not.
I feel sorry for them.
Only that taxi driver
because he had a son only 15.
His son was only 15,
I didn't know he was doing this.
To take out a cigarette
and give it to him like that,
like it's a natural thing,
like a candy or something.
Then I was very angry
because of the son.
But then he stopped smoking.
I was impressed
when I saw him again.
I hugged him and said, "You're a good,
good father, good boy, good boy."
And I immediately
went to a jewelry shop
and bought him a cross,
silver, it was not expensive,
it just happened to be
Father's Day. (Wow!)
So I gave it to him,
and I told him all this to encourage him,
to strengthen his power
to stop smoking,
because his son was still smoking
in his house
and that was very difficult
for him, to quit.
But he still did that.
So he's really a hero.
I said, "You are a hero father.
Not just a normal father."
I said, "I know it's very difficult
for you to stop smoking.
You are good, good, good,
really, really," like that.
All right, we go back to India,
the Buddha stuff;
enough with negative stuff.
Talk of positive, but this is also negative,
that's why it brought me
to tell you this kind of thing.
You see, now parents die.
And they know it,
these bad people, they know it.
And he was just married,
and then now he knew this.
He was still young,
this boy was still young.
They knew they could seduce him now.
The parents were no longer there.
Both parents died.
Only wife and husband left.
And innocent people,
being brought up
in a very good family.
Now, so, they just sweet talk him.
They didn't say, "Drink this,"
or anything.
They just said,
"Oh, you are a good boy."
"Your blessing will make us
have a better life," and all that.
And so he asked,
"What are these men drinking?"
and the servants said to him,
"Oh, Master, they are drinking
some kind of drink." Of course.
And then he said, "Does it taste good?"
They said, "Master,
in this world it's the best."
So the youth, the boy… you must know,
even though he was married,
but in India they married young,
even 15, 16 already.
So both of them were still teenagers,
so in that case said the youth,
the son of the treasurer said,
"I must have some, too."
Of course it tasted good, he liked it.
So he called the page,
meaning the servant,
to bring him first a little,
and then a little more,
and then he drank them all.
Now in no long time, those knaves,
the bad ones,
discovered that he had taken up
the habit of drinking.
Then they flocked around him.
As time went on,
the crowd that surrounded him
increased in numbers, of course.
This is the result.
Now they got themselves
into his life so easily,
as smooth as these cocktails, alcohol.
And then, this boy, the youth,
the son, would spend
a hundred or two hundred pieces
of money at a time on strong drink.
It became a habit with him after a time,
wherever he happened to be,
to pile up a heap of coins
and call out as he drank,
"Take these coins and fetch me flowers.
Take these coins
and fetch me perfumes!
This man is clever at dicing
and this man at dancing,
and this man at singing
and this man at the playing
of musical instruments.
Give this man a thousand
and this man two thousand!"
Thus did he spend his money,
and now you know the rest.
Soon he had no more.
In no long time he squandered
all the 80 crores of treasure
that formerly belonged to him,
meaning millions.
He was a millionaire,
a kind of very rich millionaire
and now he squandered it all,
all the money
left by his parents.
So, then those knaves
said to him,
the bad group of people
that slid into his life, said to him,
"Master, your wealth is all spent."
So then he said,
"Has my wife no money?"
You know, the young boy.
And then they replied,
"Yes, Master, she has."
"Well then, fetch that, too."
Fetch the money
from his wife's treasure.
And he spent all his wife's money
in precisely the same way.
This is to be expected.
I knew it would come,
as if I had read the story before.
I didn't read the story before.
It's the first time I read it today
in front of you.
It's also the first time I knew about it.
But I knew it would happen.
After drinking,
things will become like that.
Drinking and maybe also,
drugging, stuff like that,
to make it stronger, more,
more feeling, whatever.
All right. As time went on,
he sold his fields and his parks
and his gardens and his carriages.
He even disposed of the vessels
he used at meals.
All the bowls and everything,
which is really like china,
bone china or something precious.
It's not just the normal vessels.
Are you all right there?
You want to sit down or…
You can go in the front.
There is room.
You can sit there. No problem.
I saw you're uncomfortable, just sit,
sit here, it's OK.
Sit, sit here, no problem.
Everybody knows you. Don't worry.
More comfy now?
I was going to pass out.
I thought I was going to pass out.
You pass out? (Yes.)
You did?
(A lot of blessing here.)
Too much blessing?
Then you better sit down.
Because if you pass out
on top of these sisters, then...
then it's not too good, my love.
You're OK now?
You want a chair or anything?
I'm OK, Master.
You can lean on the chair,
and put your feet here.
And put your feet right here,
don't worry.
Let's continue.
So, you see, slowly he sold everything.
He sold all the utensils that he used
for eating and everything at all.
My God, it's terrible.
And then he also sold his coverlets,
for riotous living.
And his clothes, and cloaks,
his coat, and his couches even.
Not yet, don't sell this one,
I still need it.
All right, and then…
it means he sold everything.
All that belonged to him, he sold.
And the proceeds he spent
in riotous living, riotous living,
something like that,
in that kind of lifestyle.
Riotous or riotous?
(Righteous.)
No, not righteous.
No, no, riotous, meaning bad living.
(Oh, riotous.)
Riotous living.
In old age, he sold his house,
the property of his family.
And those to whom he sold his house
took possession of it
and straight away put him out,
threw him out.
What do we call it in America?
What's the name of that
when you throw somebody
out of the house?
Evicted! (Evicted.)
They evicted him.
That's it, easier for
English people to understand.
So they evicted him
out of this house straightaway.
Thereupon, taking his wife with him,
oh, poor wife,
he found a lodging near the
house wall of other people's houses.
With a broken potsherd in his hand
he would go about begging for alms.
Finally he began to eat the leavings
of other people's food, leftovers.
Oh my God, my God, that's terrible.
One day he stood at the door
of a rest house receiving leftover food
presented to him by young monks.
The Buddha saw him and smiled.
Thereupon, the elder Ananda
asked him why he smiled,
asked the Buddha why he smiled.
I'm sorry, camera.
You don't see me?
Oh, somebody crying or sleeping.
No, you don't see me
because of the camera,
sorry about that.
Because of the computer,
but otherwise your brothers and sisters
on the other side of the planet
won't be able to see me.
All right, we can't have everything.
Today it’s raining
and this is already very good.
If the Buddha knew what
we were having right now,
he would not be able to imagine.
At that time he had to walk even.
Maybe sometimes he had
a carriage from the king,
but mostly he had to walk
with all the monks.
Because too many monks,
they cannot carry them all.
Even we have just,
not even a hundred people here,
we need how many coaches,
how many cars, caravans, vans,
to bring people many times
back and forth, back and forth.
And then utensils, and pots and pans,
lucky I did not sell any of that yet,
because I didn't drink.
You have a good Master here,
a no-drinking Master.
My sofa is still here,
my bed's still out there for you,
house’s still here.
Good, and you still have
a pot and pan to cook.
You understood everything,
you over there? (Yes.)
Are you warm enough there?
(Yes.)
Did they put heaters for you?
I mean the air con,
you can turn into heater.
It's warm enough? (Yes.)
(Warm enough.)
Good, good.
And your rooms also have air con.
All right, it's much better
there than here,
especially if you have to
go to the restroom, it's better.
Here, it's not possible
because the rain is very hard.
With the wind, it flies in all directions.
You can't protect yourself with
just a raincoat or with just an umbrella.
It's good you are there,
it's good.
You still can see me anyway, right?
It's not far, right?
Yes, not far, Master.
My God,
imagine in the Buddha's time.
We couldn't have this.
The teacher,
the Buddha was smiling
and Ananda, Reverend Ananda
asked him why,
so the Buddha explained
the reason for his smile.
Saying to Ananda,
"Ananda,
just look here at Great Wealth."
Great Wealth is the name of that boy,
the one who squandered
all the properties.
"The treasurer's son, look at him.
In this very city he has squandered
twice 80 crores of treasure,"
meaning many millions of dollars.
Two times even, because one from him
and one from his wife, as well.
My God, poor wife!
But this is the Indian wife.
We, the westerner wife
or the Asian wife, we don't have this.
We'd throw him out.
Lucky for him,
he married the Indian wife.
The Indian wife, the Hindu wife,
never left her husband,
but that was before.
Nowadays, they go to college,
they drive airplanes, they drive cars,
they make Internet business,
they earn a billion, millions of dollars,
they don't care
about the husband.
In the former life, in former times,
in Au Lac (Vietnam)
we also praised the wife,
the Japanese wife,
so we have a saying like,
"Eat the Chinese food,
stay in a French house,
and marry a Japanese wife.
These are the best for your life."
For a man, his dream, a man's dream.
Nowadays, a Japanese wife is not
the Japanese wife
that is in that saying anymore.
And the Hindu wife is also…
not all of them are as the Hindu wife
like this wife in here.
They'd kick you out in no time.
Tell them go out
and beg for chutney outside.
Or sushi.
Go out and beg for sushi outside.
So, he was saying,
the Buddha continued, saying that,
"Now, accompanied by his wife,"
poor wife,
they stick to the husband
through thick and thin,
"He is begging for alms.
For if in the prime of life
this man had not squandered his wealth,
but had applied himself to business,
he would have become
the principal treasurer in this very city."
The treasurer is taking care
of the wealth of the city
or the king's entrusted treasure.
But they give this job only
to the wealthy ones
because they know they would
not, how you say… stretch your legs.
They would not steal from
the treasure of the cities
or from the king
because they had enough.
That's why his father was entrusted
to the job of treasurer.
Stretch it out, stretch
on the other side, whatever.
Be comfy.
Yes, we are at home.
And… OK, I do it for you
so that you know I also forget
my legs also have gone to sleep.
So the thing…
That's why he was a treasurer
of the king and the city.
But after he lost all his wealth,
he went out begging.
He couldn't see the king anymore
and nobody trusted him anymore.
Nobody can trust treasure or money
or possessions or anything of value
to the kind of man who drinks
or takes drugs
and squanders his own wealth
and the wealth of his wife even,
so brainless, so idiot like that.
So the Buddha was smiling,
saying that if this boy had not
squandered all his wealth
and applied that to do business,
then he would have earned double,
triple and more money
and then he would have become
the Chief Treasurer even,
not just the treasurer,
but even Chief Treasurer of this city,
the Principal Treasurer in this very city.
And if he had retired from the world
and become a monk even,
he would have attained
Arhatship.
What friends you have
drag you down or lift you up.
If he had befriended
the Buddha or the monks,
disciple monks of the Buddha,
he would have been lifted up
to Nirvana even,
to Heaven, the highest Heaven.
But he befriended these mongrels,
these drinkers.
That's why in the Bible it says,
Be thou not among the alcohol drinkers
and meat eaters even.
So you befriend whom,
you become whom.
So the Buddha even said that.
Had he become a monk even,
then he would have
attained Arhatship already
and his wife would have been
established in the fruit of the Third Path,
also spiritually elevated, his wife.
If in the middle of life
he had not squandered his wealth
but had applied himself to business
he would have become
Second Treasurer.
Meaning even though late,
but if he applied himself to business
and became richer
then at least he
would become the Vice Treasurer
if he didn't do it earlier enough.
And if he had retired from the world
and became a monk then,
he would have attained
the fruit of the Third Path
and his wife would have
been established
in the fruit of the Second Path.
Well, still not so late.
Lower level, lower position
but still OK, still not late.
If in the later years of his life,
he had not squandered his wealth
but had applied himself to business,
he would have become
the Third Treasurer,
below the Vice Treasurer.
And if he retired from the world
and became a monk,
he would have attained
the fruit of the Second Path
and his wife would have been
established in the fruit of Stream Entry.
Stream, the Sound Stream.
Beginner, the First World.
Astral, at least.
The beginning of the Stream,
Sound Hearer. The Sound Stream.
But now he had fallen away
from the wealth of a layman
and he had likewise fallen away
from the estate of an ascetic.
He had become like the heron
in the dried-up pond.
So saying, he pronounced
the following stanzas.
Buddha pronounced this:
Having led neither the holy life
nor riches won while young,
they lingered on like aged cranes,
aged, old cranes
around a fished-out pond,
meaning dried-out pond.
Hungry, no fish any more.
Having led neither the holy life
nor riches won while young,
they lie around like worn-out bows
singing about the past.
Bows. Strings and bows
and singing about the past.
"Oh, I was so-and-so…"
"I have had such-and-such…
and I have been doing such-and-such."
Always have been, gone,
finished, done, past.
Nothing for now,
nothing for the future.
This is the fate of people who have
fallen into the snare of worldly pleasure
such as drinking, intoxicants,
and making themselves slaves to
that habit, and then lost everything,
not just their wealth, their health,
their family, their future,
but also their dignity,
the most important.
All right, end of story.
We thank the Buddha and Ananda.
We thank the Buddha,
Reverend Ananda
and all people who helped in translating,
printing, putting on the Internet, etc.,
so that we have such a wonderful
reminder of a good life,
to be a practitioner.
To be a practitioner is a real good life.
Even if you are not rich,
but you are very,
you have abundant treasure inside
that nobody can take away from you.
Thank you for being attentive.
(Thank you, Master.)
You enjoyed? (Yes, Master.)
You don't dare to clap. Why?
You can clap again if you like,
if you're happy.
There's a beautiful song.
"If you're happy, clap along…"
Something like that.
I hope you're happy.
You're happy? (Yes.)
OK. Very good. Me, too.
Now then, we say so long.
Any questions?
People over there, or here?
No? No more questions?
Tell me.
The girl.
Some spiritual thing?
Yes, it's me.
Oh, my sister.
What is it, sis?
Respected Master,
we'll be leaving tomorrow.
I'd like to represent
our Aulacese (Vietnamese) disciples
in wishing you abundant health
and a hundred years of longevity.
More than a hundred years of longevity
to take care of sentient beings. (Oh!)
For the Aulacese in particular
and for worldwide disciples in general.
The whole world. (It's all work.)
These days,
we've been living in Master's love,
so we, the Aulacese
(Vietnamese) initiates,
are in such bliss and so happy.
We wish to have a chance
to see you again
and listen to your teachings.
This afternoon,
you gave us (non-alcoholic) beer
and we enjoyed it so much,
we even got "intoxicated."
Beer without alcohol!
You have to say "no alcohol."
Yes, Master. Vegan beer!
It was so delicious, (Zero alcohol.)
and we had so much fun.
Some initiates even brought home
to share Master's blessing with
the initiates in Aulac (Vietnam).
And we're so happy.
We respectfully wish you
great health and longevity.
That's all, Master.
Thank you.
Thank you, sister. Thank you, guys.
You go home and be well.
Next time, whenever there is a chance,
we'll see each other again.
Goodbye now. (Yes.)
Love you.
Love you. Bye.
Ciao, babies.